<root>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to the first verse of the book of Proverbs, who wrote the book? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Solomon 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 1:7, “The fear of the Lord is the beginning of knowledge, but fools despise ……. and ……...”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: wisdom and instruction 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In Proverbs 1:8-9, the wise king likened the instructions of a father and the laws of a mother to two things. What are they?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a graceful ornament on your head, and chains about your neck.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 1:10
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: My son, if sinners entice you, do not consent.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The fear of the Lord is the beginning of knowledge, but fools despise wisdom and instruction. Where is this found in the bible? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Proverbs 1:7
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 1:32, what destroys fools?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Complacency 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 2:6 says, “For the Lord gives wisdom; From His …….. come knowledge and understanding”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: mouth
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 2:7, “the Lord is a ……… to those who walk uprightly.” 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: shield 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 2:16-18, the house of the immoral woman leads down to ………
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: death
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “For the upright will dwell in the land, And the blameless will remain in it.” Where in the book of Proverbs is this found?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Proverbs 2:21 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 3:5
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Trust in the Lord with all your heart, And lean not on your own understanding
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 3:6
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: In all your ways acknowledge Him, And He shall direct your paths.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Do not be wise in your own eyes; Fear the Lord and depart from evil.” Where is this found in the bible?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Proverbs 3:7
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 3:13-16, what can be found in the right hand of wisdom and understanding?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: length of days 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 3:13-16, what two things can be found in the left hand of wisdom and understanding?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Riches and honor 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill the blanks: The Lord by ……. founded the earth; By ………. He established the heavens. Proverbs 3:19
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: wisdom; understanding 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In Proverbs 3:27, there is an advice not to withhold good from a certain group of people. Who are they? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Those to whom it is due
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 3:29, why does your neighbor dwell by you? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: for safety’s sake
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks: Proverbs 3:31- Do not envy the ………, and choose none of his ways
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: oppressor
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 3:33, on whose house is the curse of the Lord? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the wicked 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks: “Surely He scorns the …….., But gives ……… to the humble.”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: scornful; grace
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Wisdom is the principal thing; Therefore, get wisdom. And in all your getting, get understanding.” Where is this written in the bible? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Proverbs 4:7
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 4:18, whose path is like the shining sun, That shines ever brighter unto the perfect day.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the path of the just 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 4:23
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Keep your heart with all diligence, for out of it spring the issues of life.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Her lips drip honey, and her mouth is smoother than oil; But in the end she is bitter as wormwood, sharp as a two-edged sword. Who is she? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: an immoral woman (Proverbs 5:3-4)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 6:6, from whom should the sluggard learn wisdom? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the ant 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Which, having no captain, overseer or ruler, provides her supplies in the summer, and gathers her food in the harvest.” Proverbs 6:6-8. Of whom was this written? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the ant
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 6:9-10, what desirable deed of nature was the sluggard warned against?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: sleep-slumber
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Of the six things that the Lord hates and the seven abominations, which is the first? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a proud look (Proverbs 6:16-17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Of the six things that the Lord hates and the seven abominations, which is the last? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: one who sows discord among brethren (proverbs 6:16-19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Of the six things that the Lord hates and the seven abominations, which is the fifth? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: feet that are swift in running to evil (Proverbs 6:16-19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 6:26, who is capable of reducing a man to a crust of bread? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a harlot 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 6:27-28 says: “Can a man take fire to his bosom, and his clothes not be burned? Can one walk on hot coals, and his feet not be seared?” Which sin was the writer talking or warning about? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Adultery (Proverbs 6:27-32)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks: Proverbs 6:32 – “Whoever commits adultery with a woman lacks understanding; He who does so destroys ………..”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: his own soul
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks: “Keep my commands and live, And my law as the ………..” Proverbs 7:2
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: apple of your eye 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            With what did the seductress in Proverbs 7 perfume her bed? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: myrrh, aloes, and cinnamon. Proverbs 7:17
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The seductress of Proverbs 7 covered her bed with tapestry, Colored coverings of linen from which ancient nation? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Egypt. (Proverbs 7:16)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Concerning the seductress of Proverbs 7, it is written: With her ……….. she caused him to yield, with her …………… she seduced him
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: enticing speech; flattering lips (Proverbs 7:21)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 8:15-17 says concerning me: “By me kings reign, and rulers decree justice. By me princes rule, and nobles, all the judges of the earth. I love those who love me, and those who seek me diligently will find me.” Who/ what am I?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: wisdom (Prov. 8:12)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In one guess. Proverbs 8:35 says: For whoever finds me finds life, and obtains favor from the Lord. Who/what am I? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Wisdom (Prov. 8:12)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks: Proverbs 9:10: "The fear of the Lord is the beginning of wisdom, and the knowledge of the Holy One is ………......”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: understanding
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            "Stolen water is sweet, and bread eaten in secret is pleasant." Who says this and to whom? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a foolish woman to him who lacks understanding (Proverbs 9:13-17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 10:4 says: He who has a slack hand becomes ………, but the hand of the …………. makes rich.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: poor; diligent 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 10:22 says: The blessing of the Lord makes one rich, And He adds no ………… with it.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: sorrow
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 10:26 says: As vinegar to the teeth and smoke to the eyes, So is the ………….. to those who send him.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: lazy man
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 11:4 says: …………… do not profit in the day of wrath, but righteousness delivers from death.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Riches
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 11:14 says: Where there is no counsel, the people fall; But in the multitude of ………… there is safety.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: counselors
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            With what did Proverbs 11:22 liken a lovely woman who lacks discretion?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a ring of gold in a swine's snout
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Proverbs 11:30 says:  The fruit of the righteous is a tree of life, And he who wins souls is ………..
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: wise 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Do not give your strength to _______, nor your ways to that which destroys kings.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: women (Prov 31:3)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What reason did King Lemuel's mother give to him against drinking wine as a king?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: so they do not forget the law and pervert the justice of all the afflicted (Prov 31:5)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Give strong drink to him who is perishing and wine to those who are ______
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer bitter of heart (Prov 31:6)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Let him drink and forget his _________, and remember his misery no more 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: poverty (Prov 31:7)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Whose worth is far above rubies?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a virtuous wife (Prov 31:10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why is the virtuous woman described to be like the merchant ships?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: because she brings her food from afar (Prov 31:14)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What time does the virtuous woman rise to provide food for her household?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: while it is yet night (Prov 31:15)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does the virtuous woman do with her profits? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: she buys a field and plants a vineyard (Prov 31:16)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What time of the night does the lamp of the virtuous woman go out?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Never (Prov 31:18)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The virtuous woman stretches her hand to the distaff, and her hands holds the ________
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: spindle (Prov 31:19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why is the virtuous woman not afraid of snow for her household?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: because all her household is clothed with scarlet (Prov 31:21)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is the colour of the linen clothing of the virtuous woman?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: purple (Prov 31:22)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does the virtuous woman supply to merchants?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: sashes (Prov 31:24)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What law is found on the tongue of the virtuous woman?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the law of kindness (Prov 31:26)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The virtuous woman does not eat what kind of bread?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the bread of idleness (Prov 31:27)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who makes the statement "many daughters have done well, but you excel them all"?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the virtuous woman's husband (Prov 31:28-29)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Charm is deceitful and beauty is passing but a woman who _______, she shall be praised 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: fears the Lord (Prov 31:30)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What should praise the virtuous woman in the gates?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: her own works (Prov 31:31)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who is the father of Agur? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Jakeh (Prov 30:1)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Do not add to His words lest he ________ you and you be found a liar.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: rebukes (Prov 30:6)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why did Agur say "Give me neither poverty nor riches"?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Lest he be full and deny God saying "who is the Lord?" Or lest he be poor and steal and profane the name of God (Prov 30:8-9)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 30:10, what would make a servant to curse a person and the person will be found guilty?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: when the person maligns the servant to his master (Prov 30:10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 30:15-16, which three things are never satisfied?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the grave, the barren womb and the earth that is not satisfied with water
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What will happen to the eyes that mocks his father and scorns obedience to his mother?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The ravens of the valley will pick it out and the young eagles will eat it (Prov 30:17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who eats and wipes her mouth saying "I have done no wickedness"?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The adulterous woman (Prov 30:20)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            For three things the earth is perturbed, yes, for four it cannot bear up. What are the four things?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a servant when he reigns, a fool when he is filled with food, a hateful woman when she is married and a maidservant who succeeds her mistress (Prov 30:21-23)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What four little things on this earth are considered exceedingly wise?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The ants, the rock badgers, the locusts and a spider (Prov 30:24-28)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Which four creatures do Agur consider majestic in pace and walk?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a lion, a Greyhound, a male goat and a King whose troops are with him (Prov 30:29-31)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            As the churning of milk produces butter, the wringing of the nose produces blood, so the ________ produces stride.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: forcing of wrath (Prov 30:33)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Under whose rule do the people rejoice?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The righteous (Prov 29:2)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He who is often rebuked, and hardens his _____, will be suddenly destroyed, and that without _______
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: neck, remedy (Prov 29:1)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does he who is a companion of harlots waste?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: His wealth (Prov 29:3)

        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The king establishes the land by justice, but he who receives bribes ________ it.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer- overthrows it (Prov 29:4)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
             What does a man who flatters his neighbor do for his feet?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer- spreads a net for his feet (Prov 29:5)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does a righteous man consider about the poor?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: he considers their cause (Prov 29:7)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How is an evil man snared?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: by transgression (Prov 29:6)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 29:8, what kind of men set a city aflame?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: scoffers (Prov 29:8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Though the bloodthirsty hates him, the upright seeks his wellbeing. Who is he?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the blameless (Prov 29:10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In one guess, between the wise man and the fool, who vents all his feelings?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the fool (Prov 29:11)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What becomes of a Ruler's servants when he pays attention to lies?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the servants become wicked (Prov 29:12)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does the poor man and his oppressor have in common?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: the Lord gives light to the eyes of both of them (Prov 29:13)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What kind of judgement of the poor is required of a king for his throne to be established forever?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Judge the poor with truth (Prov 29:14)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does the rod and rebuke give to a child?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: wisdom (Prov 29:15)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            When the wicked are multiplied, ______ increases; But the righteous will see their fall
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer:  transgression (Prov 29:16)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 29:17, when a father corrects his son, he will give him two things. What are they?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: rest and delight to his soul (Prov 29:17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Prov 29:18: Where there is no revelation, the people __________
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Cast off restraint (Prov 29:18)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What kind of a man is there more hope for a fool than for him?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a man hasty in his words (Prov 29:20)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A man's pride will bring him ______, but the humble in spirit will retain honor 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: low (Prov 29:23)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What kind of man hates his own life and reveals nothing even when he swears to tell the truth?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: A man who is a partner with a thief (Prov 29:24)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Even when many seeks the Ruler's favour, who is the one that provides justice for man?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The Lord God (Prov 29:26)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who flees when no one pursues?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The wicked (Prov 28:1)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How does Proverbs 28:3 describe the poor man who oppresses the poor?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: he is like a driving rain which leaves no food (Prov 28: 3)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Those who forsake the law praise the _______.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: wicked (Prov 28:4)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            To be poor with integrity or rich and perverse, which is better?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: poor with integrity (Prov 28:6)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A son who keeps company with gluttons is regarded to what?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: shame his father (Prov 28:7)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who does the one who increases his possession by usury and extortion gather it for?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: for him who will pity the poor (Prov 28:8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How does the Bible describe the prayer of the one who turns his ear away from hearing the law?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: an abomination (Prov 28:9)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What happens to the person who causes the upright to go astray in an evil way? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: he will fall into his own pit (prov 28:10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            When the righteous rejoice, there is great glory; but what happens when the wicked arise?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: men hide themselves (Prov 28:12)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He who covers his sin will not prosper, but what does the person who confesses and forsakes his own receive?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Mercy (Prov 28:13)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The man who hardens his heart will fall into calamity, but what happens to the man who is always reverent?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: He will be Happy (Prov 28: 14)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who is regarded to be as a roaring Lion and a charging bear?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: a wicked ruler of a poor people (Prov 28:15)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What shall the person who follows frivolity receive? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: poverty (Prov 28:19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A faithful man will abound with blessings but what would happen to the man who hastens to be rich?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: he will be punished (Prov 28:20)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What kind of man hastens after riches but does not consider that poverty will come upon him?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans : a man with an evil eye (Prov 28:22)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Between the man who rebukes a man and he who flatters him with the tongue, who will find more favor afterward?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans : he who rebukes a man (Prov 28:23)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How does the Bible describe whoever robs his father and mother and says "it is no transgression"?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: a companion to a destroyer (Prov 28:24)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Whoever trusts in the Lord will be prospered but what happens to the man that is of a proud heart?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: he stirs up strife (Prov 28:25)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He who gives to the poor will not lack but what happens to the person who hides his eyes?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: you will have many curses (Prov 28:27)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How does Proverbs 28:26 describe the person who trust in his own heart?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: he's a fool (Prov 28:26)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What two things does Proverbs 27:3 say a fool's wrath is heavier than?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: stone and sand (Proverbs 27:3)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is better than love carefully concealed?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Open rebuke (Prov 27:5)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Better is a _______ nearby than a brother far away.
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: neighbor (Prov 27:10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why does a father in Proverbs 27:11 say "my son, be wise and make my heart glad"?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: so that he may Answer him who reproaches him (Prov 27:11)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is the reward of the man who blesses his friend with a loud voice, rising early in the morning?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: it will be counted as curse to him (Prov 27:14)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does Proverbs 27:15 say is similar to a contentious woman?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: a continual dripping on a rainy day (Prov 27:15)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Just like whoever keeps the fig tree will eat its fruit, so will he who waits for his master be _____________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: honored (Proverbs 26:18)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            As in water face reflects face, so a man's _______ reveals the man
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: heart (Prov 27:19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Just like hell and destruction are never full, so the ______ of man are never _________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: eyes, satisfied (Prov 27:20)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Just like the refining pot is for silver and the furnace for gold, how is a man valued?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: hey man is followed by what would I say of him ( Prov 27:21)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What happens to his foolishness when you grind a fool in a mortar with a pestle along with crushed grain?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: is foolishness would not depart from him ( proverbs 27:22 )
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            As snow in the summer and rain in harvest so _____ is not fit for a fool
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: honor (Prov 26:1)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A whip for a horse, a ________ for a donkey, and a rod for the fool's back
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: bridle (Prov 26:3)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why should we not Answer a fool according to his folly?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: lest he be wise in his own eyes (Prov 26: 5)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What action does the Bible describe as like a man cutting off his own feet and drinking violence?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: sending a message by the hand of your fool (Prov 26:6)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How does the bible describe a proverb in the mouth of fools?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: like the legs of the lame that hangs limp/like a thorn that goes into the hands of a drunkard (Prov 26:7,9)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What kind of action would be like one who binds a stone in a sling?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: giving honor to a fool (Prov 26:8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The great God who formed everything gives the fool his _____ and transgressor is _____
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: hire, wages (Prov 26:10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does a fool who repeats his folly behave like?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Like a dog that returns to his own vomit (Prov 26:11)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            "There is a lion in the road! A fierce lion is in the streets!" Who says this?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: the lazy man (Prov 26:13)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How does a lazy man turn on his bed?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: like a door turns on its hinges (Prov 26:14)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In his own eyes, the lazy man is wiser than how many men Answering sensibly?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: 7 men (Prov 26:16)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How does the Bible describe he who passes by and meddles in a quarrel not his own?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: he is like one who takes a dog by the ears (Prov 26:17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What kind of man is described to be like a madman who throws firebrands, arrows and death?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: The man who deceives his neighbor and says "I was only joking" (Prov 26:18-19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Where there is no wood, the fire goes out; and where there is no _________, strife ceases.
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: talebearer (Prov 26:20)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who is described to be like charcoal is to burning coals and wood to fire?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: a contentious man to kindle strife (Prov 26:21)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fervent lips with a wicked heart are like what?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Earthenware covered with silver dross (Prov 26:23)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The man who hates but disguises it with his lips, who lays up deceit within himself, has how many abominations in his heart?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: 7 (Prov 26:24-25)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            There is a man who hates but disguises it with his lips, who lays up deceit within himself. Where will his wickedness be revealed?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: before the assembly (Prov 26:26)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A lying tongue hates those who are crushed by it and a flattering mouth works _______
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: ruin (Prov 26:28)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who copied the Proverbs of Solomon in Proverbs 25?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: the men of Hezekiah King of Judah (Prov 25:1)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            To whose glory is it to search out a matter?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Kings (Prov 25:2)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            As the heavens for height and the earth for depth, so is ______ unsearchable?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: the heart of Kings (Prov 25:3)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Where does the silver go when you take away its dross? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: to the silversmith (Prov 25:4)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What happens when you debate your case with your neighbor and disclose the secret to another?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: he who hears it will expose your shame and ruin your reputation (Prov 25:9-10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is like an earring of gold and an ornament of fine gold?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: a wise rebuker to an obedient ear (Prov 25:12)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is said to be like Apples of gold in settings of silver?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: a word fitly spoken (Prov 25: 11)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why is the faithful messenger described to be like the cold of snow in time of harvest to those who sent him?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: because he refreshes the soul of his masters (Prov 25: 13)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The one who falsely boasts of giving is likened to?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: cloud and wind without rain (Prov 25:14)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            By long forbearance a ruler is persuaded, and a gentle tongue breaks a __________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: bone (Prov 25:15)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why does Proverbs 25:16 advise only to eat as much honey as one has?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: so you are not filled with it and vomit (Prov 25:16)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why does Proverbs 25:17 says a person should seldom set foot in his neighbor's house?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: so the neighbor doesn't become weary of him and hate him (Prov 25:17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who is said to be like a club, a sword and a sharp arrow?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: a man who bears false witness against his neighbor (Prov 25:18)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is described to be like a bad tooth and a foot out of joint?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: confidence in an unfaithful man (Prov 25:19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            If your enemy is hungry, give him bread to eat and if he is thirsty give him water to drink for so you will heap ________ on his head and the Lord will reward you.
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: coals of fire (Prov 25:21-22)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            If the North wind brings forth rain, what does a backbiting tongue bring?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: an angry countenance (Prov 25:23)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            It is better to dwell in the ______ of a housetop than in a house shared with a contentious woman.
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: corner (Prov 25:24)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is described to be like cold water to a weary soul?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: good news from a far country (Prov 25:25)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is described to be like a murky spring and a polluted well?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: A righteous man who falters before the wicked (Prov 25:26)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is described to be like a City broken down, without walls?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: whoever has no rule over his own spirit (Prov 25:28)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Whose heart devises violence and lips talk of troublemaking?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: evil men (Prov 24:1-2)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A house is built through wisdom, by what is it established?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: understanding (Prov 24: 3)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            By what are rooms filled with all precious and pleasant riches?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: By knowledge (Prov 24:4)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            By wise counsel you will wage your own war, and in a multitude of counsellors, there is ________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: safety (Prov 24:6)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who will be called a schemer?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: he who plots to do evil (Prov 24:8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            When will the strength of a man be regarded as small?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: if he faints in the day of adversity (Prov 24:10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A righteous man may fall seven times and rise again but how shall the wicked fall?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: By calamity (Prov 24:16)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What will God do when a person rejoices at the fall of his enemy or stumbles?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: The Lord will turn away his wrath from the enemy (Prov 24:17-18)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            For there will be no _______ for the evil man, the lamp of the wicked shall be put out
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Prospect (Prov 24:20)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What three things was found in the field of the lazy man and the vineyard of the man devoid of understanding?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: overgrown with thorns, covered with nettles, stone wall was broken down (Prov 24:31)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who says "Eat and drink!" but his heart is not with you?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: A miser (Prov 23:6-7)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why should one not remove the ancient landmark nor enter the fields of the Fatherless?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: because their redeemer is mighty and he will plead their cause against you (Prov 23:10-11)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is the benefit of beating a child with the rod of correction?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: You shall deliver his soul from hell (Prov 23: 14)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Do not let your heart envy ________, but be __________ for the fear of the Lord all the day.
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: sinners; zealous (Prov 23:17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is the reward of those who do not let their heart envy sinners but rather are zealous for the fear of the Lord all the day?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: their hope will not be cut off (Prov 23:17-18)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            For the drunkard and the glutton will come to poverty and _______ will clothe a man with rags
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: drowsiness (Prov 23:21)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Apart from the truth, what three other things should one buy and not sell?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: wisdom and instruction and understanding (Proverbs 23:23)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Between the preparation of the heart and the Answer of the tongue, which belongs to man?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: The preparation of the heart (Prov 16:1)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Where are all the ways of a man considered pure?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: In his own eyes/In the eyes of the man (Prov 16:2)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 16:3, what happens when you commit your works to the Lord?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Your thoughts will be established (Provb16:3)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Which abomination to the Lord would not go unpunished even if theyall join forces?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Everyone proud in heart (Prov 16:5)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In mercy and _________, atonement is provided for iniquity.
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: truth (Prov 16:6)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In which situation does the Lord makes even a man's enemies to be at peace with him?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: When a man's way please the Lord (Prov 16:7)

        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Better is a little with _______, than vast revenues without justice.
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: righteousness (Prov 16:8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A man's ______ plAns his way, but the Lord directs his steps 
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: heart (Prov 16:9)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In which area must the mouth of a king never transgress?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: judgement (Prov 16:10)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 16:12, what is an abomination for Kings?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: to commit wickedness (Prov 16:12)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who can appease the king's messengers of death?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: A wise man (Prov 16:14)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What can be found in the light of a King's face?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Life (Prov 16:15)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            How much better to get wisdom than ________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Gold (Prov 16:16)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The highway of the upright is to ___________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Depart from evil (Prov 16:17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Prov 16:18, Pride goes before ___________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Destruction (Prov 16:18)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A harlot is a deep pit and a seductress is _______
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: narrow well (Prov 23:27)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who lies in wait as for a victim and increases the unfaithful among men?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: The harlot/seductress (Prov 23:27-28)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            It bites like a serpent, it stings like a viper and makes your heart utter perverse things, what is it?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: wine (Prov 23:31-33)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 22:6 as written in the new King James version 
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Train up a child in the way he should go, and when he is old he will not depart from it
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He will reap sorrow and the rod of his anger will fail. Who is he?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: He who sows iniquity (Prov 22:8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 22:15 as written in the New King James version 
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Foolishness is bound up in the heart of a child; the rod of correction will drive it far from him
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 22:16 what shall be the end of he who oppresses the poor to increase his Riches and he who gives to the rich?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: He shall come to poverty 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 22:22-23 what will the Lord do to those who rob the poor because he is poor or oppress the afflicted at the gate?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: The Lord will plead their cause and plunder the soul of those who plunder them
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 22:29 as written in the New King James version
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Do you see a man who excels in his work? He will stand before Kings; He will not stand before unknown men
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 21:3 what is more acceptable to the Lord than sacrifice?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: To do righteousness and justice 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Getting treasures by a lying tongue is the fleeting fantasy of those who seek ________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Death (Prov 21:6)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 21:7, why will the violence of the wicked destroy them?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Because they refuse to do justice
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 21:13 what will happen to whoever shuts his ears to the cry of the poor?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: He will also cry and not be heard
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            A man who wanders from the way of understanding will rest in the assembly of ______
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: the dead (Prov 21:16)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He who loves pleasure will ______, he who loves wine and oil will ________
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: be a poor man/will not be rich (Prov 21:17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He scales the city of the mighty and brings down the trusted stronghold. Who is he?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: A wise man (Prov 21:22)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 20:1 as written in the New King James version
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: wine is a mocker, strong drink is a brawler and whoever is led astray by it is not wise 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He will not plow because of winter,he will beg during harvest and have nothing. Who is he?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: The lazy man (Prov 20:4)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Bread gained by deceit is sweet to a man, but afterward his mouth will be filled with _____
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: gravel (Prov 20:17)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What does he who goes around as a talebearer reveal?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Secrets (Prov 20:19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What happens to the one who curses his father or his mother?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: His lamp will be put out in deep darkness (Prov 20:20)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 20:29 as written in the New King James version
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: The glory of young men is their strength, and the splendor of old men is their Gray head 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He will suffer punishment, if you rescue him, you will have to do it again. Who is he?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: A man of great wrath (Prov 19:19)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            He who mistreats his father and chases away his mother is a son who causes shame and brings _______
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: reproach (Prov 19:26)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Proverbs 19:29, whose backs are beatings prepared for?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: fools 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            His lips enter into contention, his mouth is his destruction and calls for blows, his lips are the snare of his soul. Who is he?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: A fool (Prov 18:6-7)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The man who is slothful in his work is a brother to who?
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: a great destroyer (Prov 18:9)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 18:10 as written in the New King James version
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: The name of the Lord is a strong tower; the righteous run to it and are safe 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Before destruction the heart of a man is ________, and before honor is humility 
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Haughty (Prov 18:12)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 18:21 as written in the New King James version
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: Death and life are in the power of the tongue, and those who love it will eat its fruits 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Proverbs 18:22 as written in the New King James version
        </text>
        <answer>
            ANS: He who finds a wife finds a good thing, and obtains favour from the Lord
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Thus says ________ king of ________: All the kingdoms of the earth the Lord God of heaven has given me. And He has commanded me to build Him a house at Jerusalem which is in Judah.” ‭‭Ezra‬ ‭1‬:‭2‬ ‭NKJV‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Cyrus, Persia
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Ezra 1:5, who came out from the “houses of Judah and Benjamin and the priests and Levites, with all whose spirits God had moved” to build the house of God in Jerusalem?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The heads of the father’s houses 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Where did Nebuchadnezzar keep the articles of the house of the Lord which he took from the temple in Jerusalem?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: In the temple of his gods. (Ezra 1:7)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What was the name of the treasurer by whose hands King Cyrus brought out the articles of the house of the Lord?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Mithredath (Ezra 1:8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            When the articles of the house of the Lord were brought out, they were counted out to the prince of Judah. What was his name?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Sheshbazzar (Ezra 1:8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Altogether, how many were the articles of gold and silver counted before the prince of Judah?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: “All the articles of gold and silver were five thousand four hundred…” (Ezra1:11) NKJV
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Among the people of the province who came back from captivity, whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried away to Babylon, how many men were of the people of Parosh?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: “the people of Parosh, two thousand one hundred and seventy-two;” (Ezra‬ ‭2‬:‭3)‬ ‭NKJV‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Among the people of the province who came back from captivity, whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried away to Babylon, how many men were of the people of Arah?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: “the people of Arah, seven hundred and seventy five;” (Ezra 2:5 NKJV)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Among the people of the province who came back from captivity, whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried away to Babylon, how many men were of the people of Pahath-Moab, Jeshua and Joab?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: “two thousand eight hundred and twelve;” (Ezra‬ ‭2‬:‭6 ‭NKJV)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Among the people of the province who came back from captivity, whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried away to Babylon, how many men were of the people of Shephatiah?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: “the people of Shephatiah, three hundred and seventy-two;” (Ezra‬ ‭2‬:‭4 ‭NKJV‬‬)‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Among the people of the province who came back from captivity, whom Nebuchadnezzar the king of Babylon had carried away to Babylon, how many men were of the people of Elam?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: “the people of Elam, one thousand two hundred and fifty-four;” (Ezra‬ ‭2‬:‭7‬ ‭NKJV‬)‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks: “Then Jeshua the son of ______ and his brethren the priests, and ________ the son of Shealtiel and his brethren, arose and built the altar of the God of Israel, to offer burnt offerings on it, as it is written in the Law of Moses the man of God.” ‭‭Ezra‬ ‭3‬:‭2‬ ‭NKJV‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬‬
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Jozadak, Zerubbabel
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In what month of what year did all who came back from captivity to the house of God at Jerusalem begin working
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The Second month of the second year. Ezra 3:8
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What was the age range of the Levites who were appointed to oversee the work of the house of the Lord on the return to Jerusalem in Ezra 3:8?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: 20 years and above
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            'When the builders laid the foundation of the temple of the Lord , the priests stood in their Apparel with trumpets, and the Levites, the sons of ________, with cymbals, to praise the Lord , according to the __________ of David king of Israel. ' Ezra 3:10
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Asaph, Ordinance
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What did many of the priests and Levites and heads of the fathers’ houses, old men who had seen the first temple, do when the foundation of the new temple was laid before their eyes in Ezra 3:12?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: They wept with a loud voice. 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Let us build with you, for we seek your God as you do; and we have sacrificed to Him since the days of Esarhaddon king of Assyria, who brought us here.” Who made this statement?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The adversaries of Judah and Benjamin. Ezra 4:1-2
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            This was the response of Zerubbabel and Jeshua and the rest of the heads of the Fathers to the adversaries of Judah: “You may do nothing with us to build a house for our God; but we alone will build to the Lord God of Israel, as King Cyrus the king of Persia has commanded us.” TRUE OR FALSE?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: True. Ezra 4:3
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The people of the land tried to discourage the people of Judah from building the house of God. During whose reign did they write an accusation against the inhabitants of the land of Judah and Jerusalem which led them to cease building the temple?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: King Ahasuerus. Ezra 4:6
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Who has commanded you to build this temple and finish this wall?” According to Ezra 5:3, who asked this question?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Tattenai the governor of the region beyond the River and Shethar-Boznai and their companions.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            'Now therefore, if it seems good to the king, let a search be made in the king’s treasure house, which is there in Babylon, whether it is so that a decree was issued by King Cyrus to build this house of God at Jerusalem, and let the king send us his pleasure concerning this matter.' The quote above is an excerpt from a letter sent to a King. What was his name?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: King Darius. Ezra 5:7, 17
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In what year of the reign of Cyrus, King of Babylon did he issue the decree to build the house of God?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The First year. Ezra 5:13
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What was the name of the place where King Darius found the scroll containing the decree made by king Cyrus to build the house of God?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Achmetha (Ezra 6:2)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            On what day of which month was the rebuilding of the temple of God completed?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: On the third day of the month of Adar. Ezra 6:15
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In what year of the reign of King Darius was the temple of God completed?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: The Sixth year. Ezra 6:15
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            When the children of Israel celebrated the completion of the temple of God, how many male goats did they offer as a sin offering for all of Israel?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Twelve. Ezra 6:17
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            'Then I proclaimed a fast there at the river of _________, that we might humble ourselves before our God, to seek from Him the right way for us and our little ones and all our possessions. ' Ezra 8:21
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Ahava
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Why was Ezra ashamed to request an escort of soldiers and horsemen from the king?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: He was ashamed to ask because he had spoken to the king saying, “The hand of our God is upon all those for good who seek Him, but His power and His wrath are against all those who forsake Him.” (Ezra 8:22)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            'Now on the fourth day the silver and the gold and the articles were weighed in the house of our God by the hand of ________ the son of Uriah the priest, and with him was Eleazar the son of Phinehas; with them were the Levites, Jozabad the son of Jeshua and Noadiah the son of Binnui, ' Ezra 8:33
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: Meremoth.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            'So when I heard this thing, I tore my garment and my robe, and plucked out some of the hair of my head and beard, and sat down astonished. 'What report did Ezra receive that made him react this way?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: He received news that the Isrealites, especially the leaders have not separated themselves from the other nations and have taken wives from among them. Ezra 9:1-3
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Ezra chapter 10, what did the children of Israel who had trespassed by taking foreign wives for themselves do to turn the wrath of God away from them?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Answer: They put away all their foreign spouses and their offsprings.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Which word started the book of Hebrews? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: God. Heb. 1:1
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 1, by who has God spoken in these last days? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: His son. Heb. 1:2
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 1:2 “whom He has appointed heir of all things, through whom also He made the worlds”. In one guess, who was the passage referring to? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Jesus Christ (the Son)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Complete this passage, Hebrews 1:3 “who being the brightness of His glory and the express image of His person, and upholding all things by the word of His power, when He had by Himself purged our sins, sat down at the …………… of the Majesty on high”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: right hand
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 1:4, God’s son by inheritance obtained a more excellent name than ……….. ?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the angels
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Hebrews 1:8 says: “But to the Son He says, “Your throne, O God, is forever and ever;
A scepter of ………. is the scepter of Your kingdom”

        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: righteousness
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Of whom was this written in Hebrews 1:8-10: “You, LORD, in the beginning laid the foundation of the earth, and the heavens are the work of Your hands.”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: The son (Jesus Christ)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Hebrews 1: 11-12 says: “They will perish, but You remain; and they will all grow old like a garment; Like a cloak You will fold them up, and they will be changed.” What was this referring to that will perish? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the earth and the heavens. Heb. 1:10
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 1:14, certain creatures are ministering spirits sent forth to minister for those who will inherit salvation. What are these creatures? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Angels 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Hebrews 2:1 says: “Therefore we must give the more earnest heed to the things we have heard, lest we ………...” 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: drift away     
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Hebrews 2:3 says: “how shall we escape if we neglect so great a ……………., which at the first began to be spoken by the Lord, and was confirmed to us by those who heard Him”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: salvation
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Hebrews 2:9 says: “But we see Jesus, who was made a little lower than ………….., for the suffering of death crowned with glory and honor, that He, by the grace of God, might taste death for everyone.”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the angels
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 2:10, Jesus Christ, the captain of our salvation was made perfect through his sufferings. True or False? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: True
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Through what did Jesus Christ destroy him who had the power of death, that is, the devil and release those who through fear of death were all their lifetime subject to bondage? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Death. Heb. 2:14-15
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In Hebrews 3:1, who was called the Apostle and High Priest of our confession?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Christ Jesus
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Complete Hebrews 3:4: “For every house is built by someone, but He who built all things is ………..”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: God
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
             In Hebrews 3:7-8, who says: “Today, if you will hear His voice, do not harden your hearts as in the rebellion, in the day of trial in the wilderness”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: The Holy Spirit
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 3:7-10, for how long did the fathers test, try God and see his works in the wilderness? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: forty years 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            As recorded in Hebrews 3:7-11, the Holy Spirit swore against that generation of the fathers because of their rebellion saying: ‘They always go astray in their heart,
And they have not known My ways.’  What was the swear pronouncement?

        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: ‘They shall not enter My rest.’ 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Hebrews 3:13.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: but exhort one another daily, while it is called “Today,” lest any of you be hardened through the deceitfulness of sin. 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “For the word of God is living and powerful, and sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing even to the division of soul and spirit, and of joints and marrow, and is a discerner of the thoughts and intents of the heart.” Where is this found in the bible? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Hebrews 4:12
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Complete this verse: “And there is no creature hidden from His sight, but all things are naked and open to the eyes of Him to whom we must …………...
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: give account. Hebrews 4:13
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
             “Let us therefore come boldly to the throne of grace, that we may obtain mercy and find grace to help in time of need.” Where is this found in the bible?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Hebrews. 4:16
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the gaps. Hebrews 5:12-13 “For though by this time you ought to be teachers, you need someone to teach you again the first principles of the oracles of God; and you have come to need milk and not solid food. For everyone who partakes only of milk is ……….. in the word of righteousness, for he is a babe.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: unskilled
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Complete this verse. Hebrews 5:14, “But solid food belongs to those who are of full age, that is, those who by reason of use have their senses exercised to discern both …………….”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: good and evil
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In Hebrews 6, six concepts were called the elementary principles of Christ. Name any 4. 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the foundation of repentance from dead works, and of faith toward God, of the doctrine of baptisms, of laying on of hands, of resurrection of the dead, and of eternal judgment. Heb. 6:1-2
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            When God made a promise to Abraham, by whom did he swear? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: by Himself. Heb. 6:13
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 6:13-14, what was the promise God made to Abraham? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: “Surely blessing I will bless you, and multiplying I will multiply you.”
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 6:18, we who have fled for refuge lay hold of the hope set before us, have strong consolation. Why? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: it is impossible for God to lie
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 6:19, this hope we have is as an anchor of the …………., both sure and steadfast, and which enters the Presence behind the veil.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Soul 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            There was a king mentioned in Hebrews 7:1. Spell his name.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: M-e-l-c-h-i-z-e-d-e-k 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews, Melchizedek had two offices. What were they? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: king of Salem, and priest of the Most High God. Hebrews 7:1
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who did Melchizedek meet returning from the slaughter of the kings and blessed him? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Abraham. Hebrews 7:1
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 7:2 and 4, what did Abraham give to the king of Salem? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: a tenth of all (the spoils). 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            What is the meaning of “king of Salem”?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: king of peace. Heb. 7:2
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            I am someone without father, without mother, without genealogy, having neither beginning of days nor end of life, but made like the Son of God, and remain a priest continually. In one guess, what is my name? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Melchizedek. Heb. 7:3
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Levi paid tithe to Melchizedek. True or False?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: True. Heb. 7:9-10
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 7:7, beyond all contradiction the better is blessed by the lesser. True or False? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: False 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Our Lord arose from a tribe of which Moses spoke nothing concerning priesthood. In one guess, what tribe was that? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Judah. Heb. 7:14
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 7:20-21, “He was not made priest without an oath.” Who was He?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Jesus Christ 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            All or none question. According to Hebrews 7:27, in the Levitical priesthood, the high priest daily offers sacrifices for sin for two set of sinners. Whose sin was he to offer sacrifices for? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: His own sins and then for the people’s. 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks: Hebrews 8:1, “Now this is the main point of the things we are saying: We have such a High Priest, who is seated at the …………. of the throne of the Majesty in the heavens”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: right hand
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            When Moses was about to make the tabernacle, he was instructed thus: “See that you make all things according to the pattern shown you on ………...”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the mountain. Heb. 8:5
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “For if that first covenant had been faultless, then no place would have been sought for a second.” Where is this found in scriptures? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Hebrews 8:7
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill the blanks. Hebrews 8:10 says “For this is the covenant that I will make with the house of Israel after those days, says the LORD: I will put My laws in their mind and write them on ………….; and I will be their God, and they shall be My people.”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: their hearts
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill the blanks. Hebrews. 8:13 says “In that He says, “A new covenant,” He has made the first obsolete. Now what is becoming obsolete and growing old is ready to ……………….”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: vanish away
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The tabernacle of the first covenant had a sanctuary. What were the things found therein? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the lampstand, the table, and the showbread. Heb. 9:1-2
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            The part of the tabernacle of the first covenant which was behind the second veil is called what? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the holiest of all. Heb. 9:3
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In the first covenant’s tabernacle, the part behind the second veil had the golden censer and the ark of the covenant. With what was the ark of covenant overlaid on all sides? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Gold. Heb. 9:4
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In the tabernacle, was the ark of covenant. In the ark of covenant was the golden pot. What was found in the golden pot? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the manna Heb. 9:4
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Apart from the golden pot, what else was found in the ark of covenant of the tabernacle of the first covenant? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Aaron’s rod that budded, and the tablets of the covenant. Heb. 9:4
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Above the ark of covenant of the tabernacle of the first covenant were the cherubim of glory overshadowing ……………..
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the mercy seat. Heb. 9:5 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            There was a part of the tabernacle the high priest entered only once every year. What part was it?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the second part (or the holiest of all). Heb. 9:7
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            While going into the part of the tabernacle he enters only once a year, how many people does the high priest enter with? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: no one. He goes alone. Heb. 9:7
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            I am something special. While going into the part of the tabernacle he enters only once a year, the high priest cannot go without me. What am I? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Blood. Heb. 9:7
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 9:11, Who came as High Priest of the good things to come, with the greater and more perfect tabernacle not made with hands, that is, not of this creation?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Christ. 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Not with the blood of goats and calves, but with what did Christ enter the Most Holy Place once for all, having obtained eternal redemption?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: his own blood. Heb. 9:12
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill the blanks. “For if the blood of bulls and goats and the ashes of a heifer, sprinkling the unclean, sanctifies for the purifying of the flesh, how much more shall the blood of Christ, who through the eternal Spirit offered Himself without spot to God, cleanse your …………….. from dead works to serve the living God?”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: conscience. Heb. 9:13-14
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Concerning Christ, it is written: “And for this reason He is the Mediator of the new covenant, by means of …………………., for the redemption of the transgressions under the first covenant, that those who are called may receive the promise of the eternal inheritance.”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: death. Heb. 9:15
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 9:16-17, “For where there is a testament, there must also of necessity be the death of the testator. For a testament is in force after men are dead, since it has no power at all while the testator lives.” True or False
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: True 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks. Hebrews 9:19: “For when Moses had spoken every precept to all the people according to the law, he took the blood of calves and goats, with water, scarlet wool, and ………….., and sprinkled both the book itself and all the people.”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: hyssop
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Hebrews 9:27
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: And as it is appointed for men to die once, but after this the judgment.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In Hebrews 10:1, the old law was described not as the image itself of good things to come but as what? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: a shadow 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 10:4, it is possible that the blood of bulls and goats could take away sins in the old covenant. True or False? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: False
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill the blanks. Concerning Christ, Hebrews 10:9 says, “He said, “Behold, I have come to do Your will, O God.” He takes away the ……………. that He may establish the …………………..”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: first; second 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Concerning Christ in Hebrews 10:12, it is wri tten, “But this Man, after He had offered one sacrifice for sins forever, sat down at …………………”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: the right hand of God
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 10:19-20, the veil of the first covenant was replaced by what in the new covenant? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Christ’s flesh. 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Not forsaking the assembling of ourselves together, as is the manner of some, but exhorting one another, and so much the more as you see the Day approaching.” Where is this found in the New Testament? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Hebrews 10:25
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 10:28, anyone who has rejected Moses’ law dies without mercy on the testimony of how many witnesses?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: two or three witnesses
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks. Hebrews 11:3 says, “By …………. we understand that the worlds were framed by the word of God, so that the things which are seen were not made of things which are visible.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: faith
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Answer in one guess. I offered to God a more excellent sacrifice than my brother, through which I obtained witness that I was righteous, God testifying of my gifts; and through it I being dead still speak. Hebrews 11:4. Who was my brother? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Cain
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            By faith I was taken away so that I did not see death, “and was not found, because God had taken me”; for before I was taken I had this testimony, that I pleased God. Who am I? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Enoch. Heb. 11:5
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Hebrews 11:6
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: But without faith it is impossible to please Him, for he who comes to God must believe that He is, and that He is a rewarder of those who diligently seek Him.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            By faith I obeyed when I was called to go out to the place which I would receive as an inheritance. And I went out, not knowing where I was going. Who am I? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Abraham. Heb. 11:8
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Hebrews 11:9-10 says: “By faith he dwelt in the land of promise as in a foreign country, dwelling in tents with Isaac and Jacob, the heirs with him of the same promise; for he waited for the city which has foundations, whose builder and maker is God.” In one guess, who was he? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Abraham (vs 8)
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Hebrews 11: 12 says, “Therefore from one man, and him as good as dead, were born as many as the stars of the sky in multitude—innumerable as the sand which is by the seashore.” Of whom was this written? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Abraham 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 11:17-19, by what conclusion (or reason) did Abraham offer up Isaac his only begotten son at God’s request? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: he concluded that God was able to raise him up, even from the dead. 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Who, by faith, while he was dying made mention of the departure of the children of Israel, and gave instructions concerning his bones? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Joseph. Heb. 11:22
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            By faith, when he was born, was hidden three months by his parents, because they saw he was a beautiful child; and they were not afraid of the king’s command. Who was he?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Moses. Heb. 11:23
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill in the blanks. Hebrews 11:24-26: By faith …………… when he became of age, refused to be called the son of Pharaoh’s daughter, choosing rather to suffer affliction with the people of God than to enjoy the passing pleasures of sin, esteeming the reproach of Christ greater riches than the treasures in Egypt; for he looked to the reward.
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Moses
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
             By faith the walls of Jericho fell down after they were encircled for how many days?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: 7 days. Heb. 11:30
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Even though she was a harlot, she did not perish with those who did not believe, when she had received the spies with peace. Spell her name. 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: R-A-H-A-B. Heb. 11:31
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Looking unto Jesus, the author and finisher of our faith, who for the joy that was set before Him endured the cross, despising the shame, and has sat down at the right hand of the throne of God.” Where is this written in the New Testament?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Hebrews 12:2
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “My son, do not despise the chastening of the LORD, nor be discouraged when you are rebuked by Him; For whom the LORD loves He chastens, and scourges every son whom He receives.” In 2 guesses. Which chapter of the book of Hebrews talks about the chastening of the Lord?
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Hebrews 12
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Fill the blanks. Hebrews 12:16 says, “Lest there be any fornicator or profane person like ……………., who for one morsel of food sold his birthright.”
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Esau
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            According to Hebrews 12:24, whose blood speaks better things than that of Abel? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Jesus Christ
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
             Fill the blanks. Hebrews 12:28-29 says, “Therefore, since we are receiving a kingdom which cannot be shaken, let us have grace, by which we may serve God acceptably with reverence and godly fear. For our God is a …………………….
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: consuming fire
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Hebrews 13:1. 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Let brotherly love continue.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            In Hebrews 13:2, Christians were admonished to entertain strangers. Why? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: by so doing some have unwittingly entertained angels.
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Marriage is honorable among all, and the bed undefiled; but fornicators and adulterers God will judge.” Where is this found in the book of Hebrews? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Hebrews. 13:4
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            Recite Hebrews 13:8
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Jesus Christ is the same yesterday, today, and forever. 
        </answer>
    </question>
    <question>
        <text>
            “Therefore by Him let us continually offer the sacrifice of praise to God, that is, the fruit of our lips, giving thanks to His name.” Where in the New Testament is this written? 
        </text>
        <answer>
            Ans: Heb. 13:15
        </answer>
    </question>
</root>
